thebudgetmom.com 2019-03-28

# PRIVACY POLICY - The Budget Mom

Our Privacy Policy was last updated and posted on **May 14, 2018**. It governs the privacy terms of our Website, located at https://www.thebudgetmom.com/. Any capitalized terms not defined in our Privacy Policy, have the meaning as specified in our [Terms of Service](https://www.thebudgetmom.com//disclaimer/).

##  **Your Privacy**

The Budget Mom, LLC and <https://www.thebudgetmom.com/> follows all legal requirements to protect your privacy. Our Privacy Policy is a legal statement that explains how we may collect information from you, how we may share your information, and how you can limit our sharing of your information. You will see terms in our Privacy Policy that are capitalized. These terms have meanings as described in the Definitions section below.

##  **Definitions**

“Non Personal Information” is information that is not personally identifiable to you and that we automatically collect when you access our Website with a web browser. It may also include publicly available information that is shared between you and others.

“Personally Identifiable Information” is non-public information that is personally identifiable to you and obtained in order for us to provide you within our Website. Personally Identifiable Information may include information such as your name, email address, and other related information that you provide to us or that we obtain about you.

##  **Information We Collect**

Generally, you control the amount and type of information you provide to us when using our Website.

As a Visitor, you can browse our website to find out more about our Website. You are not required to provide us with any Personally Identifiable Information as a Visitor.

##  **Personally Identifiable Information**

We may process certain types of personal data about you when you interact with us, as follows:

  *  **Identity Data:** may include your first name, last name, username, or date of birth.
  *  **Contact Data:** may include your billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
  *  **Financial Data:** may include your credit card details.
  *  **Transaction Data:** may include details about payments between us and other details of purchases made by you.
  *  **Technical Data:** may include your login data, internet protocol addresses, browser type and version, browser plug-in types and versions, time zone setting and location, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access our sites.
  *  **Profile Data:** may include your username and password, purchases or orders, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
  *  **Usage Data:** may include information about how you use our website, products and services.
  *  **Marketing and Communications Data:** may include your preferences in receiving marketing communications from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

##  **Computer Information Collected**

When you use our Website, we automatically collect certain computer information by the interaction of your mobile phone or web browser with our Website. Such information is typically considered Non Personal Information. We also collect the following:

  *  **Cookies**  
Our Website uses “Cookies” to identify the areas of our Website that you have visited. A Cookie is a small piece of data stored on your computer or mobile device by your web browser. We use Cookies to personalize the Content that you see on our Website. Most web browsers can be set to disable the use of Cookies. However, if you disable Cookies, you may not be able to access functionality on our Website correctly or at all. We never place Personally Identifiable Information in Cookies.
  *  **Automatic Information**  
We automatically receive information from your web browser or mobile device. This information includes the name of the website from which you entered our Website, if any, as well as the name of the website to which you’re headed when you leave our website. This information also includes the IP address of your computer/proxy server that you use to access the Internet, your Internet Website provider name, web browser type, type of mobile device, and computer operating system. We use all of this information to analyze trends among our Users to help improve our Website.

##  **How We Use Your Information**

We use the information we receive from you as follows:

  *  **Customizing Our Website**  
We may use the Personally Identifiable information you provide to us along with any computer information we receive to customize our Website.
  *  **Register You as a Customer**  
We use Personally Identifiable information you provide us to deliver products and services, process your payments, and register you as a customer.
  *  **Sharing Information with Affiliates and Other Third Parties**  
We do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your Personally Identifiable Information to third parties for marketing purposes. We may provide your Personally Identifiable Information to affiliates that provide services to us with regards to our Website (i.e. payment processors, Website hosting companies, etc.); such affiliates will only receive information necessary to provide the respective services and will be bound by confidentiality agreements limiting the use of such information.

The following third parties may have access to your Personally Identifiable Information:

  *     * ConvertKit (Portland, OR USA)
    * Google Apps (Mountain View, CA USA)
    * Google Analytics (Mountain View, CA USA)
    * Facebook via our Facebook groups (Menlo Park, CA USA)
    * PayPal (San Jose, CA USA)
    * Leadpages (Minneapolis, MN USA)
  *  **Data Aggregation**  
We retain the right to collect and use any Non Personal Information collected from your use of our Website and aggregate such data for internal analytics that improve our Website and Service as well as for use or resale to others. At no time is your Personally Identifiable Information included in such data aggregations.
  *  **Legally Required Releases of Information**  
We may be legally required to disclose your Personally Identifiable Information, if such disclosure is (a) required by subpoena, law, or other legal process; (b) necessary to assist law enforcement officials or government enforcement agencies; (c) necessary to investigate violations of or otherwise enforce our Legal Terms; (d) necessary to protect us from legal action or claims from third parties including you and/or other Members; and/or (e) necessary to protect the legal rights, personal/real property, or personal safety of The Budget Mom, LLC., our Users, employees, and affiliates.

##  **Transferring Information**

By using this website, you authorize us to transfer and store your information in the United States, for the purposes described in this policy. The privacy protections and the rights of authorities to access your information in the United States may not be the same as in your home country.

##  **Marketing communications**

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have:

  * Requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us; or
  * Provided us with your details when opting into our free courses, resources, and challenges; and  
in each case, you have not opted out of receiving marketing.
  * We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party for marketing purposes.

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you OR by emailing us at kumiko@thebudgetmom.com at any time.

Where you opt out of receiving our marketing communications, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, warranty registration, product/service experience or other transactions.

##  **EU Residents:**

If you wish to exercise your “right to be forgotten” and have all Personally Identifiable Information deleted, please email us directly with your request: kumiko@thebudgetmom.com.

You maintain the right to complain to the Data Protection Authority in your local EU Member State under the GDPR.

##  **Data Security**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed.

In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know such data. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

Customer data is stored for a reasonable time (5+ years) as a necessity to keep accurate records of accounting, tax, and customer needs. The exact data retention period varies based on the system storing the information, the date of the user’s last activity or interaction with the company, and whether or not the information relates to a current or past customer.

##  **Links to Other Websites**

Our Website may contain links to other websites that are not under our direct control. These websites may have their own policies regarding privacy. We have no control of or responsibility for linked websites and provide these links solely for the convenience and information of our visitors. You access such linked Websites at your own risk. These websites are not subject to this Privacy Policy. You should check the privacy policies, if any, of those individual websites to see how the operators of those third-party websites will utilize your personal information. In addition, these websites may contain a link to Websites of our affiliates. The websites of our affiliates are not subject to this Privacy Policy, and you should check their individual privacy policies to see how the operators of such websites will utilize your personal information.

##  **Privacy Policy Updates**

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. You should review this Privacy Policy frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we may notify you on our Website, by a blog post, by email, or by any method we determine. The method we chose is at our sole discretion. We will also change the “Last Updated” date at the beginning of this Privacy Policy. Any changes we make to our Privacy Policy are effective as of this Last Updated date and replace any prior Privacy Policies.

## Advertising Privacy Statement

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact us at kumiko@thebudgetmom.com ** ** and contact AdThrive at [info@adthrive.com](mailto:info@adthrive.com). If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences link at the bottom of the site. (Available in the EU.)

##  **Questions About Our Privacy Practices or This Privacy Policy**

If you have any questions about our Privacy Practices or this Policy, please contact kumiko@thebudgetmom.com.

The Budget Mom  
PO BOX 638  
Chewelah, WA 99109

Email Address:  
kumiko@thebudgetmom.com

Effective as of May, 14th 2018.
